https://www.smd.co.uk/privacy/

INTRODUCTION
Welcome to our Privacy Notice.
We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data.  This Privacy Notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data, tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.
WHO WE ARE
SMD is made up of the following group of companies which are covered by this Privacy Notice in the UK:
Soil Machine Dynamics Limited
Specialist Machine Developments (SMD) Limited
SMD Offshore Support Limited
SMD Robotics Limited
This Privacy Notice is issued on behalf of these four companies, so when we mention ‘SMD’, ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘our’ in this Privacy Notice, we are referring to the relevant company in our group responsible for processing your data.  They are all registered at Turbinia Works, Davy Bank, Wallsend, Tyne and Wear, NE28 6UZ, UK.
WHEN WE COLLECT PERSONAL DATA ABOUT YOU
Personal data means any information about you as an individual from which you can be identified.
These are the main ways we collect your information:
If you decide to contact us, whether directly by email, telephone or via our website. For example, to request information about our products or services, to submit an enquiry, to ask us to provide a quote or when you submit your CV.
If you buy a product or service directly from us.
If you sell a product or service to us.
If you opt-in to our mailing list.
If we acquired your personal data from other sources, for example social media sites or a business card you have provided to us.
As you interact with our website, though the use of cookies and Google Analytics. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information.
WHAT PERSONAL DATA MAY BE COLLECTED ABOUT YOU
The following types of personal data about you may be collected:
Contact Details, including name, address, phone numbers, email addresses.
The company you work for and your job title.
Bank details if we enter into a contract, purchase order or payment arrangement with you.
Injury details in the unlikely event you suffer an accident whilst on our premises.
Your vehicle registration number if you visit our premises.
CCTV footage whist you are on our premises.
CV information, education and employment history and qualifications if you submit this to us in advance of or when applying for a job or training course (we have a separate more detailed privacy notice which we provide to job candidates).
When visiting our website, your browser type, IP address, details of how you accessed the website and the pages you visited, through cookies and Google Analytics.
HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We will use your personal data as required for us to provide the relevant services or to handle your enquiry appropriately.  For example, providing you with a quote or setting you up as a customer or supplier on our IT systems.  We may use your personal data to assess your suitability for a vacancy if you have submitted information to us for this purpose.  We will also use your personal data to tailor our mailing lists and inform you about our latest news and opportunities if you have opted-in to receive such emails.
We use cookies and analytical information gathered when you visit our website to help us understand how you use the website and to make changes to the layout, content and/or performance of the website.  For more information on cookies, please see paragraph 11 below.
We may also use your personal data where necessary to carry on our day-to-day business, to provide a safe environment on our site, to comply with our legal and contractual obligations and to protect our property and assets.
WHY ARE WE ALLOWED TO USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to.  The use of your personal information set out above is permitted under UK data protection laws in the following circumstances:
Where you have explicitly given us your consent to use your personal data. This applies when signing up to our mailing list.  You can withdraw your consent at any time.  To do so either click ‘unsubscribe’ in the footer of any mailshot email you receive from us, or send an email to us at marketing@smd.co.uk.
Where it is necessary to perform a contract or purchase order we have entered into or are about to enter into with you.
Where it is necessary for us to achieve a legitimate interest and our reasons for doing so outweigh any potential risk to your data protection rights.
Where we need to comply with our legal obligations.
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose.  If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
WHO DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH?
We have controls in place to limit access to your information to our employees who need it to do their job, such as dealing with your enquiry, or producing a quote for you.
In certain circumstances, we may share your information with selected service providers who perform functions on our behalf, such as providing our site security, providing and/or hosting our IT and telephony systems, processing and running our mailing lists, running our enterprise resource planning (ERP) system, hosting our website and other support and maintenance services.  Our service providers will only use your information to the extent necessary to perform their functions.
We may also, if requested and where required, provide your personal data to our advisers, including our lawyers, insurers, accountants and auditors.  Where it is required or permitted by law, we may also provide your personal data to organisations such as law firms or insurance companies acting on behalf of other individuals or companies, who may request evidence of CCTV or other evidence containing personal data to support a claim in relation to an incident or accident on our site.
DATA SECURITY
We place a great deal of importance on the security of all personal data.  We have technical and organisational security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, alteration and access by third parties of your personal information under our control.  These may include encryption, security certificates, access controls, information security technologies, policies and procedures.
We have put in place measures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying and legal, accounting or reporting requirements, after which time we shall either make your information non-identifiable or delete it.
YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.
You have the right to withdraw consent from being subscribed to our mailing list at any time.  See paragraph 5 for more detail.
You have the right to request the personal data we hold about you as well as request the correction, or restriction of your personal data.  In some instances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal data or request the erasure of the personal data we hold on you.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us by emailing commercial@smd.co.uk.  You will not have to pay a fee to exercise any of these rights, however we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive of excessive.  Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month.  Occasionally it may take us longer than one month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests.  In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
This Privacy Notice does not cover links within our website linking to other non-SMD websites.  If you follow a link to a non-SMD website, please note our Privacy Notice does not apply and you should familiarise yourself with that company’s own privacy notice.  We do not accept responsibility or liability for information supplied to those websites.
COOKIES
Cookies are small files saved to your computer that track, save and store information about your interactions and usage of our website.   This allows our website to provide you with a tailored and enhanced experience, by speeding up navigation, improving functionality and keeping track of our website visitors.  You can disable or delete cookies in your internet browser settings.
When you visit our website, we use a third party service called Google Analytics to track visitor usage of our website, and which pages are visited by you and others, so we can improve the quality of our website and its contents.
REVISION
This is Revision 2 of our Privacy and Cookies Policy, now called ‘Privacy Notice: General’ and is dated 24 May 2018.
Reference SPEC-OTH-TCS-SPC-002 ‘Privacy Notice: General’
© 2019 Soil Machine Dynamics Ltd. All rights reserved.
This website uses cookies to ensure you get the best experience. Please read our cookie policy for more information
Accept
